Guide to the McCloud B. Hodges Papers, 1960-1999
Hodges, McCloud B. papers, 1960-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
McCloud Hodges papers, 1960-1999.
3516
McCloud B. Hodges
3 cubic ft., Tape recordings: 1 reel, 3 cassettes.
Correspondence, manuscripts, tape recordings, published articles
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, speeches, published articles and reports, papers, and manuscripts concerning real estate investment; land valuation tax; computer applications in real estate, education, taxation and ethics; rent control; and the American Institute of Real Estate Appraisers. Includes material concerning ethics, professionalism and techniques of real estate appraising. Also, four tape recordings, one with a transcript. Also subject files: Land Economics, Political Economy, Valuation and Finance, Virginia State Appraiser License, Property Tax Research, Ethics and Professionalism, Taxation, Bay Program and Lawn Care Seminars, and Investment Class.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Real estate investment property appraiser and counselor.
Hodges' practice is located in Arlington, Virginia. Member, International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, George Washington Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, speeches, published articles and reports, papers, and manuscripts concerning real estate investment; land valuation tax; computer applications in real estate, education, taxation and ethics; rent control; and the American Institute of Real Estate Appraisers. Includes material concerning ethics, professionalism and techniques of real estate appraising. Also, four tape recordings, one with a transcript. Also subject files: Land Economics, Political Economy, Valuation and Finance, Virginia State Appraiser License, Property Tax Research, Ethics and Professionalism, Taxation, Bay Program and Lawn Care Seminars, and Investment Class.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hodges, McCloud B.,; American Institute of Real Estate Appraisers.; Lambda Alpha International.George Washington Chapter.
Subjects:
Real property.; Real property--Valuation.; Land valuation tax.; Real estate investment--Law and legislation.; Real estate appraisers.; Real estate appraisers--Legal status, laws, etc.; Real estate counselors.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Part of Lambda Alpha Literary Archives.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Boxes 3 and 4: chronological.
CONTAINER LIST
- Land economics, 1969-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Land economics (oversize), 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Political economy, 1969-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Political economy (oversize), 1974-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Valuation and financing, 1987-1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Virginia State Appraiser License, 1973-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Property tax research, 1973-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ethics and professionalism, 1978-1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Taxation, 1973-1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Bay program and lawn care seminars, 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Investment class: real estate tax reform, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Investment class: real estate tax reform (oversize), 1985-1986, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- (#1) Appraising, seminars on appraising, 1962, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- (#2) Real estate appraising articles, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- (#4) Real estate appraising: articles, hearing, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- (#5) Licensing, appraising, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- (#6) Appraising, mortgages, Congressional subcommittee testimony, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- (#2) Appraisal regulations, letters, new tools for analysis, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- (#8) Computer use in analysis, appraisal, real property tax, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- (#9) Computer aplications in real estate appraisal, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- (#9) Introduction to mortgage equity capitalization (oversize), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Appraisal, land valuation, computers, local AIREA, investment, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- (#11) DCF appraisal methods, investment, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- (#12) Electronic tools schedule, realestate analysis package, investment, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- (#13) Klamath Indian Trust (timberland): deposition highlights, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- (#14) Program, statement, letter to editor, capitalization rate problems, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Statement before D. C. Council re: licensing real estate appraisers (oversize), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- (#15) Mortgages, valuation, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- (#16) Contingent fee, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Rates of tax, computer assisted value numbers, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- (#18) L'Enfant Plaza Properties, Inc.; land development law; DCF programs, Lambda Alpha, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- (#19) Pfeffernuesse Philanthropies vs. after-tax DCF; Lambda Alpha archives at C. U., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- (#20) Subdivision analysis; DCF, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- (#21) Economic pitfalls of ERTA, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- (#22) Capitalization problems; award winner in Appraisal Journal, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- (#23) Reprint, letters to editor re: effects of taxes, reasons for high costs of residential appraisals, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- (#24) Spreadsheet confusion in DCF, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Appraisal of 5011 Wilson Boulevard, Arlington, Virginia, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Annotated bibliography for modernization in valuation of investment in classed real estate, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- An overview of property tax relief for homeowners, National Conference of State Legislatures Fiscal Affairs Program, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- State tax policy options for the elderly: a guide for aging advocates, National Association of State Units on Aging, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Significant features of fiscal federalism, Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Significant features of fiscal federalism, Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, volume 1, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Valuation notes, articles, correspondence, legal document, 1980-1994 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
- Real estate tax relief for elderly and handicapped, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Fuzzy set theory: an introduction to its application for real estate analysis, Gene Dilmore, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Real estate and the capital gains debate, Michael Hudson and Kris Feder, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)